<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-03-17T20:00:00+10:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>pairing-tools-and-where-to-find-them</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/03/17/pairing-tools-and-where-to-find-them.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/03/17/pairing-tools-and-where-to-find-them.html</id>
    <published>2015-03-17T20:00:00+10:00</published>
    <updated>2015-03-17T20:01:34+10:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id="current-status-9-down-43-to-go"&gt;Current Status: 9 down, 43 to go.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past weeks, I've been experimenting with a number of pairing tools, I've been trying to wrestle with the great tragedy that is Australian upload speeds when pairing with developers from all over the world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news, is that there are plenty of tools out there, but which one suits you? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="screenherohttpscreenherocom"&gt;&lt;a href="http://screenhero.com"&gt;Screenhero&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Screenhero is a great screen-sharing tool, and will soon come bundled with Slack to enable users to screenshare from their chat environment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support for dual mouse cursors, means its easy to collaborate on the same bit of code and communicate where that missing &lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt; lies. The audio and screen visibility provided you have good upload and download speeds is pretty excellent. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote screensharing tool, it also enables you to pair on more visual aspects of your application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, this service is free, whilst it's being integrated with Slack, but new user registrations are closed, however if you can snag an invitation from an existing user, you can continue to use it free of charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="floobitshttpfloobitscom"&gt;&lt;a href="http://floobits.com"&gt;Floobits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've only stumbled on floobits rather recently, but if you're looking for a tmux like experience for minimal latency and collaboration. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It enables users to pair via workspaces, which will enable synching of files between the developers working on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where floobits really shines, besides the low latency pairing functionality, is its support for multiple editors. This means you can each bring your own keybindings to the party, and continue to be productive. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don't use an editor with a floobits extension, there is a web interface available, which is reasonably robust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it's monthly cost can be prohibitive, but if you're not a vim user and are working on open source projects, this is an exceptionally good tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="tmuxtmatehttptmateio--vim"&gt;Tmux/&lt;a href="http://tmate.io"&gt;Tmate&lt;/a&gt; + Vim&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the ultimate low latency way to pair. Tmux is a fantastic tool in and of itself, but combined with Vim, makes it easy to remote pair. No workspaces means you're editing your pairs code, which removes the guesswork out of where stuff lies. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Utilising tmate, a fork of tmux, it becomes incredibly simple to connect to a shared tmux session, whilst still being able to utilise your &lt;code&gt;tmux.conf&lt;/code&gt; file. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, not everyone is a Vim user, and when pairing you are ultimately bound to your pairs &lt;code&gt;.vimrc&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;tmux.conf&lt;/code&gt; configuration settings. However, this can also be a particularly useful way of picking up new vim plugins or more comfortable key-bindings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally as I'm becoming more of a fan of the Vim workflow, im leaning towards Tmux and Vim, but Floobits offers a great alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Three down, forty nine to go</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/02/06/three-down.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/02/06/three-down.html</id>
    <published>2015-02-06T18:17:00+10:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-06T20:12:47+10:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Pairing is the best way to improve your code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd heard this from a Ben
Orenstein talk this week, where he referenced another developer and surmised
that pairing with both those of less skill and more skill than you is a great
way to improve yourself as a developer. With 3 pairing sessions down, I'm already
starting to find myself in agreement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first session was with Rachelle, and we had a look at working on the testing
and feature development of an existing application she was working on as part of
the &lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/Brisbane-Coder-Club/"&gt;Brisbane Coder Club&lt;/a&gt;. Rachelle
and I have been friends for some time, so this session was awesome for just
getting into the groove and working on some features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up was Kevin, who is working on some really interesting translation
software, whilst I struggled to grasp fully all the moving parts of his gem and
application, he was exceedingly patient and generous with his time and
knowledge. Together we looked for perfomance gains in the gem, as well as trying
to determine how to optimise an import task he had put together. It really
helped to encourage me to stay in the uncomfortable zone and embrace my lack of
knowledge as an opportunity to learn more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isaac, from Chicago and I got the ball rolling on some initial planning and
construction of his track application. Whilst we had a few technical issues, he
too was extremely patient and generous with his time. I really appreciated the
time he took to explain the domain, which enabled me to assist him with the
early planning, and work on the tests and features together. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Location so far, has not been an issue, and thankfully (horrible upload speeds
be damned), I've been able to work on my pairs machines so far. What has been
interesting with the varied locations, is the varying life experiences,
backgrounds and entry into Ruby of the 3 participants, making those connections
is frankly, awesomesauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going forward I will be adjusting the program slightly, as I'm looking to
encourage more people to work with me on my own project if they're interested so
I don't only spend x no of hours on theres from a week to week basis. If this is
something that interests you, please, get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd like to thank Rachelle, Kevin and Isaac for being such awesome pairs, and
will update here again soon with how the next sessions went.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
